Nataly Moreno-Martinez

Github: https://github.com/nmprojects

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/nataly-moreno-martinez/

ABOUT ME

Senior Software Developer who specializes in full-stack app development, mathematical modeling, with expertise in cloud technologies/infrastructure and pipeline architecture. Mixing Python, C#, and custom Bash/Shell scripting for most projects, experience with many other languages and frameworks for professional development. Avid learner of the latest tools and platforms; currently exploring computer hardware, AI, and the global internet.

SKILLS SUMMARY

Python, R, C#, C, C++, VB, Bash, Matlab, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL, Racket, Lisp Languages

.NET, WPF/XAML, Scikit, OpenCV, Flask, ReactJS, NextFlow, Luigi Docker, Git, PostgreSQL, IIS, Visual Studio, VS Code, Vim Frameworks

Tools

Platforms Linux, Web, Google Cloud Platform, Azure, AWS, JIRA, GitHub, Bitbucket

OOP, SOLID, Agile Development, Unit and Integration Testing, Mathematical Modeling, Machine Learning Concepts

Communication, Problem-Solving, Collaboration, Discipline Soft Skills

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Developer, CAS Project

Bruker NANO, formerly PhenomeX

March 2023 - Present

Email: nmmsoftware@gmail.com

Mobile: +1-505-203-6058

- o Completed a full-scale Azure DevOps migration in record 3 months by coordinating team efforts, automating migration processes, and creating custom programmatic tools.
- Expedited application runtime by 75% with code rewrite, hitting product specifications with an on-time release.
- Built critical testing functionality ahead of schedule, expediting product release by 2 weeks.
- Enriched deployment life cycle and scalability through Docker and CI/CD orchestration technologies.
- Constructed a multi-cloud implementation of Genomic sequencing testing infrastructure.

Senior Software Developer, Duomic Project

Remote

Remote

IsoPlexis Corp., a PhenomeX Company

Dec 2022 - March 2023

• Increased critical application performance by 400% by leading a re-architecture of existing code.

- Improved software quality and throughput by implementing DevOps pipeline refactoring and automated testing.
- Supported interdepartmental teamwork by developing python libraries, custom tools, and high-quality documentation to be shared and referenced.
- Worked with company leadership to create technology solutions that achieved high-level business goals.

Software Developer

Remote

IsoPlexis Corp., a PhenomeX Company

Jan 2022 - Dec 2022

- o Main developer in creating research tools for next-gen sequencing.
- Independently developed a web portal that enabled interdepartmental teams to access research tools.
- Introduced automated unit testing and integration testing into our development packages.
- Worked with C++ computer vision libraries to improve our sequencing technologies.

Computer Systems Engineer

Remote

McMaster-Carr

Sep 2021 - Jan 2022

- o Improved company knowledge sharing and education by creating an internal communications hub.
- Worked with established SDLC that involved cross team coordination, testing, and release schedules.
- o Delivered business value by developing website features end to end, including Database Schemas, Business Logic, REST API Implementation, and front-end development.
- Integrated legacy systems to interface with modern business-critical applications.

EDUCATION

Yale University

New Haven, CT

Bachelor of Science - Biomedical Engineering (Focus on Biocomputation); GPA: 3.64

August 2017 - May 2021

Courses and Areas of Study: Data Structures, Data Science, Analysis of Algorithms, Biomedical Imaging and Device Development, $Computation\ for\ Research,\ Mathematical\ Modeling,\ High-Performance\ High-Throughput\ Programming,\ Memory\ Management$

HONORS/AWARDS, OTHER

- Runner Up Yale CBIT (Center for Biomedical Innovation Technology) Healthcare Hackathon Jan 2021
- Tsai City Accelerator (Yale Tsai Center For Innovative Thinking) program Nov 2020.
- Yale Domestic Summer Award May 2020.
- Cum Laude. Vincent Cordova Diversity Award. National Hispanic Scholar. National Academy of Future Physicians and Medical Scientists Award of Excellence Nominee.
- Fluent in English, Spanish, French.